<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Probability on Dinkum Data Blog</title>
    <link>https://adelr.github.io/tags/probability/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Probability on Dinkum Data Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <managingEditor>adel.rahmani&#43;dinkumdata@gmail.com (Adel Rahmani)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>adel.rahmani&#43;dinkumdata@gmail.com (Adel Rahmani)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://adelr.github.io/tags/probability/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>That ain&#39;t dancing Sally!</title>
      <link>https://adelr.github.io/2018/08/simul_t_test/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>adel.rahmani&#43;dinkumdata@gmail.com (Adel Rahmani)</author>
      <guid>https://adelr.github.io/2018/08/simul_t_test/</guid>
      <description>Same difference.
Congratulations! Your simulation code from the previous post has impressed all and sundry and you&#39;ve been asked to teach introductory statistics to first year students at the prestigious Vandelay University. You&#39;ve got 2 stats classes, one with a group of 65 students, and another with a group of 35 students. We assume that the students have been randomly allocated to each group, and that they share the same final exam.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Happy birthday to you!</title>
      <link>https://adelr.github.io/2018/06/simul_birthday/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>adel.rahmani&#43;dinkumdata@gmail.com (Adel Rahmani)</author>
      <guid>https://adelr.github.io/2018/06/simul_birthday/</guid>
      <description>The Birthday Problem is a classic problem in probability theory. We will use it to illustrate how to use simulation to get an estimate of the probability of some event occuring.
Imagine that you are at a party with $N$ people (including yourself). Let&#39;s assume that we have 365 days in a year and that the birthday of the people attending the party is randomly distributed with a uniform distribution, meaning that each of the 365 days is equally probable as a birthday (if you were born on February 29, you&#39;ll need to go to another party).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do you feel lucky?</title>
      <link>https://adelr.github.io/2018/06/simul_coin_flip/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>adel.rahmani&#43;dinkumdata@gmail.com (Adel Rahmani)</author>
      <guid>https://adelr.github.io/2018/06/simul_coin_flip/</guid>
      <description>A coin flipped 100 times comes up heads 60 times. How likely is it that the coin is fair?
This is a basic example of statistical inference, trying to infer an estimate of some quantity (here the probability for heads) from some data (observation of 100 coin flips). This type of problem is invariably described in every first year stats course. To solve it, we first need to represent the underlying process generating our observations in a mathematical form.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>